<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Shang-Yu Su]]></title><description><![CDATA[master's student in National Taiwan University, research interests cover Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, and dialogue systems.]]></description><link>https://www.shangyusu.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 18:14:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[How Time Matters: Learning Time-Decay Attention for Contextual Spoken Language Understanding in Dialogues]]></title><description><![CDATA[Shang-Yu Su, Pei-Chieh Yuan, and Yun-Nung Chen]]></description><link>https://www.shangyusu.com/posts/naacl2018-nlu/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.shangyusu.com/posts/naacl2018-nlu/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Cite the paper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot;&gt;
      &lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;@inproceedings{su2018how,
  title={How time matters: Learning Time-Decay Attention for Contextual Spoken Language Understanding in Dialogues},
    author={Shang-Yu Su, Pei-Chieh Yuan, and Yun-Nung Chen},
    booktitle={Proceedings of NAACL-HLT},
    year={2018}
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoken language understanding (SLU) is an essential component in conversational systems. Most SLU components treats each utterance independently, and then the following components aggregate the multi-turn information in the separate phases.
In order to avoid error propagation and effectively utilize contexts, prior work leveraged history for contextual SLU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, most previous models only paid attention to the related content in history utterances, ignoring their temporal information.
In the dialogues, it is intuitive that the most recent utterances are more important than the least recent ones, in other words, time-aware attention should be in a decaying manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, this paper designs and investigates various types of time-decay attention on the sentence-level and speaker-level, and further proposes a flexible universal time-decay attention mechanism.
The experiments on the benchmark Dialogue State Tracking Challenge (DSTC4) dataset show that the proposed time-decay attention mechanisms significantly improve the state-of-the-art model for contextual understanding performance (The source code is at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MiuLab/E2E-Time-SLU&quot;&gt;https://github.com/MiuLab/E2E-Time-SLU&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Natural Language Generation by Hierarchical Decoding with Linguistic Patterns]]></title><description><![CDATA[Shang-Yu Su*, Kai-Ling Lo*, Yi-Ting Yeh, and Yun-Nung Chen (co-first author)]]></description><link>https://www.shangyusu.com/posts/naacl2018-nlg/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.shangyusu.com/posts/naacl2018-nlg/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Cite the paper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot;&gt;
      &lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;@inproceedings{su2018natural,
  title={Natural Language Generation by Hierarchical Decoding with Linguistic Patterns},
    author={Shang-Yu Su, Kai-Ling Lo, Yi-Ting Yeh, and Yun-Nung Chen},
    booktitle={Proceedings of NAACL-HLT},
    year={2018}
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Natural language generation (NLG) is a critical component in spoken dialogue systems.
Classic NLG can be divided into two phases: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sentence planning: deciding on the overall sentence structure, &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;surface realization: determining specific word forms and flattening the sentence structure into a string. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many simple NLG models are based on recurrent neural networks (RNN) and sequence-to-sequence (seq2seq) model, which basically contains a encoder-decoder structure; these NLG models generate sentences from scratch by jointly optimizing sentence planning and surface realization using a simple cross entropy loss training criterion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the simple encoder-decoder architecture usually suffers from generating complex and long sentences, because the decoder has to learn all grammar and diction knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper introduces a hierarchical decoding NLG model based on linguistic patterns in different levels, and shows that the proposed method outperforms the traditional one with a smaller model size.
Furthermore, the design of the hierarchical decoding is flexible and easily-extendible in various NLG systems (The source code is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MiuLab/HNLG&quot;&gt;https://github.com/MiuLab/HNLG&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dynamic Time-Aware Attention to Speaker Roles and Contexts for Spoken Language Understanding]]></title><description><![CDATA[Po-Chun Chen*, Ta-Chung Chi*, Shang-Yu Su*, and Yun-Nung Chen (co-first author)]]></description><link>https://www.shangyusu.com/posts/asru2017/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.shangyusu.com/posts/asru2017/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Cite the paper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot;&gt;
      &lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;@inproceedings{chen2017dynamic,
  title={Dynamic Time-Aware Attention to Speaker Roles and Contexts for Spoken Language Understanding},
  author={Chen, Po-Chun and Chi, Ta-Chung and Su, Shang-Yu and Chen, Yun-Nung},
  booktitle={Proceedings of ASRU},
  year={2017}
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoken language understanding (SLU) is an essential component in conversational systems.
Most SLU components treat each utterance independently, and then the following components aggregate the multi-turn information in the separate phases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to avoid error propagation and effectively utilize contexts, prior works leveraged history for contextual SLU.
However, the previous models only paid attention to the content in history utterances without considering their temporal information and speaker roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In dialogues, the most recent utterances should be more important than the least recent ones.
Furthermore, users usually pay attention to 1) self history for reasoning and 2) others’ utterances for listening, the speaker of the utterances may provides informative cues to help understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, this paper proposes an attention-based network that additionally leverages temporal information and speaker role for better SLU, where the attention to contexts and speaker roles can be automatically learned in an end-to-end manner.
The experiments on the benchmark Dialogue State Tracking Challenge 4 (DSTC4) dataset show that the time-aware dynamic role attention networks significantly improve the understanding performance (The released code: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MiuLab/Time-SLU&quot;&gt;https://github.com/MiuLab/Time-SLU&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Speaker Role Contextual Modeling for Language Understanding and Dialogue Policy Learning]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ta-Chung Chi*, Po-Chun Chen*, Shang-Yu Su*, and Yun-Nung Chen (co-first author)]]></description><link>https://www.shangyusu.com/posts/humane-typography-in-the-digital-age/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.shangyusu.com/posts/humane-typography-in-the-digital-age/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Cite the paper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot;&gt;
      &lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;@inproceedings{chi2017speaker,
  author    = {Ta-Chung Chi and Po-Chun Chen and Shang-Yu Su and Yun-Nung Chen},
  title	    = {Speaker Role Contextual Modeling for Language Understanding and Dialogue Policy Learning},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of IJCNLP},
  year	    = {2017}
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Language understanding (LU) and dialogue policy learning are two essential components in conversational systems.
Human-human dialogues are not well-controlled and often random and unpredictable due to their own goals and speaking habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper proposes a role-based contextual model to consider different speaker roles independently based on the various speaking patterns in the multi-turn dialogues.
The experiments on the benchmark dataset show that the proposed role-based model successfully learns role-specific behavioral patterns for contextual encoding and then significantly improves language understanding and dialogue policy learning tasks (The source code is available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MiuLab/Spk-Dialogue&quot;&gt;https://github.com/MiuLab/Spk-Dialogue&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>